Josh Woodcock // Front-End Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w00 // j0w0.com // linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

Front-End Software Engineer experienced in building reliable, manageable, and scalable websites and web applications. I develop quality products by utilizing appropriate technologies and applying best practices for data organization and code optimization.

Skills/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, React, Gatsby, Node, Express, Google Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Styled Components, Bootstrap, PHP, Git, creating/consuming RESTful APIs (Google, Stripe, Twilio), Wordpress CMS, WooCommerce.

Project Demos: React demos include Event Manager and Celebrity Name Game. JavaScript demos include Robots vs. Babies, Simon, and Rock, Paper, Scissors. Code and more information is available on my GitHub.

Experience

Front-End Software Engineer

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021-Present | Austin, Texas

- Develops front end of brand and artist livestream web apps that provide fans with the ultimate digital music experience. Features include event registration and voting, real-time chat, tips/donations via Stripe, and livestream video feed.
- Simplified development process for quicker turnaround by creating standardized templates for content and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, Styled Components, Google Firebase, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Front-End/UX Developer

Remedy | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined urgent care web app that helped win two stages of funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Twilio, WooCommerce.

MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Architected/developed custom Wordpress theme and plugins allowing for easier management and sharing of content.
- Developed and maintained full-stack web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer and exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.
- Tech stack used includes PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Twilio, Stripe.

Digital Media Marketing Coordinator

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

Maintained earlier versions of the company's website, event landing pages, and staff Intranet.

Education

Texas State University

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas | May 2014

General Assembly

Software Engineering | Austin, Texas | October 2020